Welcome to the
eLearning session,
欢迎来到 eLearning 课程
"Getting Started with
Ensemble and HL7 Messages."
Ensemble 和 HL7 消息入门。
Let's look at an HL7
message in Ensemble
让我们通过消息浏览器
through the Message Browser.
来看一下 Ensemble 中 HL7 消息
Notice that Ensemble
understands the message
注意，Ensemble 是理解这些消息的
and gives us hover text
capabilities to help the user
并且能给出悬浮文本帮助用户
know what each field represents.
理解每个字段代表什么。
Ensemble takes a few things
to understand the message
Ensemble 会用一些细节来理解消息///////////////////////////////////?????
that we will talk about later.
我们会在后面讲解到。
The first thing we can
note is that the message
首先，我们注意到一个消息
has a DocType Category.
有一个文档类 (DocType Category)
Often, we call this a Schema.
常常，我们称其为 Schema.
I can then look at the
contents of the message
然后，我来看一下消息的内容
and hover over a field
to see which field it is.
将鼠标悬停在字段之上，来看该字段是什么。
Notice here we can
tell that English is
这里可以注意到，English 是
the PrimaryLanguage.identifier.
PrimaryLanguage.identifier.
Ensemble stores all of these
standard HL7 definitions
Ensemble 存有所有的标准 HL7 的定义
as well as any custom
schemas inside it.
也包括用户自定义的 schemas.
Let's find the same Schema 2.3.1
in the Interoperate menu item
让我们在 Interoperate 菜单中找到同样的 Schema 2.3.1
and look at the HL7
v2.x Schema structures.
然后查看 HL7 v2.x 的 Schema 结构。
Notice here are all of our
defined Schemas, both standard
注意到，这里有我们所有定义的 Schemas,
and custom.
包括标准的和用户自定义的。
Demo.HL7.MsgRouter.Schema
is a custom schema
Demo.HL7.MsgRouter.Schema 就是一个用户自定义 Schema.
that we've pre-defined.
是我们预先定义的。
We can think of them as a
set of message definitions.
我们可以认为他们是一组消息定义集。
Inside of a schema, we have
different message types.
在一个 schema里，我们有不同的消息类型。
Now, some of these messages
actually hold the same data,
当前，有些消息实际上含有相同的数据，
but for different reasons.
但是有不同的目的。
For example, an ADT_A01
message and ADT_A08 message
比如， 一个 ADT_A01 消息和一个 ADT_A08 消息
look exactly the same with the
only difference being purpose.
看上去是完全一样的，但是在目的上有所不同。
While an ADT_A01 message
is an admit message,
ADT_A01 消息时一个入院消息，
ADT_A08 updates
a patient record.
而 ADT_A08 则是修改病人记录。
Therefore, in
Ensemble, we specify
因此，在 Ensemble, 我们指定
that both messages share
the same Message Structure.
这两个消息共享同样的消息结构。
To find a Message
Structure, we have segments.
我们通过片断 (segments) 查找消息结构。
For example, the PID segment
holds patient identification
比如，PID 片断持有病人身份
information.
辨识信息
Inside a segment, we have fields
like Patient Name or Patient
在这个片断内，我们有字段，病人姓名或
Address.
病人地址。
And for each field,
there can optionally
这里，每个字段可以是由
be sub-fields or components.
子字段或部件构成。
In Ensemble, HL7 messages are
stored as instances of the HL7
在 Ensemble 中，HL7 消息存储在 HL7 类////////////////////?????
class ENSLIB.HL7Message.
ENSLIB.HL7Message。
This is a special type of class
known as a Virtual Document.
这是一个特殊的类，被称之为虚拟文档。
The class has a
number of properties,
这个类有一些属性，
but most are not
set by the user.
但是大部分不是由用户设置而成。
They are calculated from
the content of the message.
他们通过消息的内容计算而得。
To access segments within
the message or fields
可以通过虚拟属性路径 (Virtual Property Path)
在消息内访问片断，
within a segment, you use
the Virtual Property path.
或是在片断内访问字段.
For example, an ADT_A01 message
will have fields such as MSH:9
比如，一个 ADT_A01 消息有字段 MSH:9
PID:2.1.
These can also be referred to by
the names of the fields defined
这些也可以通过标准定义的
in the standard.
字段名字引用。
For example, in version
2.3.1 ADT_A01 message,
比如，版本 2.3.1 ADT_A01 消息，
these would be the MSH,
message type, and PID,
MSH 为消息类型 (message type)
PatientIDExternalID.ID.
PID 为病人外部号 (PatientIDExternalID.ID).
For Ensemble to
currently access a value,
当前，Ensemble 为了访问到一个值
it needs to know three things.
它需要知道三件事情。
One, the virtual property path.
第一，虚拟属性路径 (virtual property path)
For example, PID:2.1.
如，PID:2.1.
The message structure.
消息结构。
For example, ADT_A01.
比如，ADT_A01.
And the schema category.
以及 schema 类别
For example 2.3.1.
比如，2.3.1.
This may be a standard
HL7 version 2 document,
这也许是一个 HL7 版本 2 的标准文档
or it could be a
custom schema category.
或者也可以是用户自定义的 schema 类别。
This is needed because the
structure in different versions
需要 schema 的原因是消息结构在不同版本
can be very different.
可能是不同的。
A schema category is normally
associated with a message
一个 schema 类别通常在消息
when it is created
and not changed.
生成的时候关联起来，不能再改变。/////////////////////////////???
At run time, Ensemble uses the
schema category and message
在运行的时候，Ensemble 利用 schema 类别
structure and
virtual property path
消息结构以及虚拟属性路径
to locate the right
place in the message.
定位到消息中合适的地方。
There are three primary
places where virtual property
有三个主要的地方需要用到
paths are used.
虚拟属性路径。
Routing Rules, Data
Transformations,
路由规则，数据转换，
and in Caché Object Script.
和 Caché 对象脚本。
We'll focus on the first two, as
using Object Script in the HL7
我们会关注在前两个，至于在 HL7 中
is a little bit more advanced.
使用对象脚本，有些略为超前。//////////////////////////////////???
The way they are
used vary slightly,
在如何使用上，有些略微不同，
but the property path is
the same in each case.
但是属性路径在每个例子中都是一样的。
Let's first look at
the Routing Rule.
让我们看一下路由规则。
If we look at this
rule, we'll notice here
我们看这规则时候，在此我们会发现
that we have in the constraint
that our schema is 2.3.1
我们有个约束条件是 schema 须是 2.3.1
and we can infer that the
message structure is ADT_A01.
并且我们可以推断消息结构是 ADT_A01.
If we go into the Condition,
to have Ensemble give us some
如果我们进入到条件 (Condition),
为了使 Ensemble 给我们提供选项
options, we have to type
HL7.{, and then we can type
我们输入 HL7.{, 然后我们可以输入
in the rest of
the property path.
剩下的属性路径。
In a Data Transformation to be
able to look at the property
在数据转换中，也可以看属性路径，
path, you'll notice here
in our property we have
你可能会在此注意到，我们的属性有
target.target.[? PID.PatientID.ID ?]
and
target.target.[? PID.PatientID.ID ?] 和
source.source.[? PID.PatientID.ID ?]
So we are still using that
所以我们还是在使用
property path.
属性路径。
Thank you for watching
this eLearning session.
感谢您收看 eLearning 课程。
We hope you learned
a little bit more
我们希望您能从中学到
about getting started with
Ensemble and HL7 Messages.
关于 Ensemble 和 HL7 消息的入门知识。